Silas Silikhe

A fierce nerd with a knack for tinkering with new technologies looking to establish myself as an expert in the Android and Cloud ecosystem. I have experience that spans close to 2.5 years.

www.silikhe.com (254) 706-745561 Github @silikhe silaswans@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Moringa School, Nairobi — Software Developer TM

MARCH 2022 - PRESENT

Responsibility:

- Lead and coordinate classroom activities
- Responsibility for class and young developer success
- Kick off and run all daily activities such peer review etc

Africa Tech Center, Nairobi — *Android Developer Trainer*

Feb 2022 - May 2022

- Trainer for the Android & Kotlin development training in ACAT and TVETs-Kenya.
- Ensuring Google and Government of Kenya meet the end goal of training software developers with the set KPIs
- Monitoring and helping(technical Mobile + Kotlin) trainees across Kenya Vocational centers

Wiggles Technology, Nairobi — *Fullstack Developer*

May 2020 - Feb 2022

- Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- Unit-testing code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency

EDUCATION

Moringa SCHOOL, Nairobi — Certificate

Jan 2021

Android Development

JKUAT, Juja — *Degree*

MONTH 2018

Bsc. Operations Research

SKILLS

Android

- Java, Kotlin
- Gradle
- Retrofit
- IUint
- Firebase

Fullstack Development

- React
- JavaScript
- PHP, Yii2
- Angular
- Nodels
- Express